what's up everybody this is neon dream
games and this week I have been working
in aprite and I've got a couple things
to show you couple different thoughts
this is another Dev vog stick around and
we will get into
[Music]
it okay well as I said at the beginning
I have been working a little bit with a
Sprite this week just kind of testing
the waters I did buy the pixel lab
plugin which allows for AI to assist you
in creating pixel art a little faster
but there are some pluses and minuses to
that I'll get into that shortly here as
I show you a little bit of what I've
been doing but also I'm testing out a
little bit of a new setup here you might
not even be able to tell a difference
but I got a new webcam the insta 360
link
Toc and I also am using OBS Studio
Studio to do everything so I can kind of
switch different scenes pretty easily
and have a couple different setups here
to share my screen and talk to you guys
and get my microphone working again
anyways just some behind the scenes
things wanted to tell you about and
before I get going I also would
appreciate it if you guys would like my
videos and subscribe to my channel if
you find that I'm providing any value to
you or you just enjoy see seen my
journey I would greatly appreciate it it
does really help grow my business really
this is for me this is a business
Endeavor and yeah I I just appreciate
that so without further Ado I have been
working this week on pixel art I
mentioned in a in a previous video that
I wanted to try and release pixel art
asset packs on platforms such as
itch.io and try and utilize that as a
passive income source so to speak after
I've been diving into aprite I don't
know if I want to do that anymore it's
it's been it's been a lot more work than
I thought not that I was just expecting
things to be easy but even with the AI
assistance there is a lot of tweaking in
fact let's just get into it let's not
delay any further I am going to share my
screen and here we go this is the kind
of first idea I had this is my
essentially my Laura Croft knockoff
character basically I called her a
female Adventurer and sort of described
her clothes and everything and it spit
out some different things this is kind
of what I came up with I guess I could
show sort of I was going to create a
character I could say I want a female
Adventurer we're going to say white tank
top jean shorts Brown we'll say brown
leather belt Brown hiking boots brunette
hair color in a ponytail oops in a
ponytail anyways okay so then we're
going to say we want a sidescroller type
thing which is like keeping it eye Lev
you know Pro more of a profile thing
facing the camera so that she's facing
the camera right now we're going to do
lineless basic shading low detail I
believe so I'm trying to learn this
plugin a bit more and basically you have
these different things flat shade in
fact actually I'm going to do flat
shading cuz I think the less you do with
the shading and the low detail it gives
a simpler look like this but I really
had to clean this up so I just want to
kind of show you quick Target palette
we're going to say the color palette
that I have so these were the colors I
kind of narrowed down with her up in
that corner up there and anyways we're
going to say a new frame and you hit
generate and you have to wait for just a
little bit to see this thing generate
but this is sort of what I I did and
it's quite interesting how it works and
this one it looks like she's a little
bit going to end up coming out a little
bit skewed not quite facing the camera
but you'll get the you'll get the idea
here all right so there was that
honestly I don't really think that's
very good or what I was hoping for so
you know you could either retry I could
go back back and try to change some of
this stuff I can use my actual image as
a reference you know so I could maybe
say the strength I don't know we'll just
say that and we will just try to
generate again just for fun and see what
happens anyways that's the pixel lab
plugin and I had to do a lot of tweaking
the final image and again we're going to
just quick see if it can generate a new
one for me I was surprised at how much I
would have to edit but it is nice to
have a kind of a starting point and
that's going to just keep going so I'm
going to switch back full screen and
talk a little bit I want to be able
ultimately I want to work on games
that's why we're here I want to work on
games and I haven't touched any games I
want to get back into tutorials I want
to try releasing asset packs but I'm
just not sure that that is worth my time
and effort so I don't know we'll see
what I do I'm going to keep messing
round a little bit in as Sprite and see
what happens okay let's flip back over
here so this is what it came up so it
kind of matched my image and everything
and this doesn't look terrible you can
see the preview this is closer I think
to what side it might even be that size
realistically on the screen I have a 4k
monitor here so anyways there's the
preview of how it looks but again if I
go back and look at mine I think mine
looks better and I touched it up I I I I
gave it detail in the places I think
that it needs detail so yeah we're going
to cancel out of this I just wanted to
show that as an example so we got these
kind of cruddy ones but anyways I'm
going to delete delete these frames and
I just want to show you so like right
there so I went from this you can rotate
your characters that's kind of an
interesting thing so it's like rotate
rotate and I don't know I guess just for
fun we will rotate so we have East
looking character and and we want to
make them look Northeast so that's going
to be starting to turn away from the
camera I I don't think I need to use an
init image but we're going to we'll see
what happens using the color palette
we're going to generate a new frame and
see if it can turn her the other way but
right now yeah I guess I'm just sort of
walking you through my process I created
this character I don't even know what I
was going to use her for I don't super
love the I don't know what you call it
the chibi type shorter stubbier
characters in in games I like a more
human proportioned normal human
proportioned character look at you can
see this is coming in actually quite
nicely that that's how fast it did that
now obviously you would have to like
touch this up but this is a good start
you know you get in here and I can you
know close this up make sure her shorts
are correct and everything and yeah you
can just sort of see how this works
anyways I'm not going to sit here and
touch this up but I'm actually pretty
happy with how that looks I'm definitely
going to have to touch it up to match
the rest of what I've done but you can
make a whole character turn around and
that's how quick that went so that's
kind of cool but that's kind of a best
case scenario it took me a long time so
I'm just going to show you I was messing
around with some animations so like sort
of like an idol animation in this one I
just sort of made her arms and torso and
chest kind of like she was breathing or
something I don't love it I feel like
there needs to be something different
and I what I did to do this let me see
if I can show you I did the animation
animate with skeleton you can kind of
see it here in fact I probably have it
pose there you go she's got a skeleton
on her and I'm just going to cancel out
of that for right now anyways you can
you know basically tell it each frame
you can essentially do skeleton
animation with this but it has such
varying results and I'm not going to
show it all to you here but I'm going to
hide that skeleton layer and I'm just
going to show you this idle 2 animation
where I sort of I tried to add her her
legs into it and it just sort of looks
like she's spazzing out or something I
don't love it so I'm going to come back
to the idle animation I don't exactly
know what I want to do to to that but
then I started working on a walk
animation and this I really actually
like I like that quite a bit but this
took me a long time obviously the
program helped me do things quicker but
in the end I sort of Wonder did it
actually go quicker or or was the amount
of time that I had to edit things and
tweak things would it have been faster
if I just started from scratch it's kind
of a big question mark I think this
looks pretty good for what it is but if
I wanted to sell this character or do
something like that I would have to
create a lot more animations and it
would take a lot more time and I don't
really know what I'd get in the end for
selling it if this is a character people
are looking for I guess you know if you
guys are developers and wanting a
character like this is this something
that you would consider buying if I
continued to to make it but this is sort
of my test character so she's just sort
of walking and yeah she's sort of my
Tomb Raider knockoff girl this was the
image I started with that I tweaked but
I also was working on like trying to go
back to that art style I don't super
love but this is a goblin I mean goblins
are small anyways but this is more of
the smaller chibi sort of Animation
stuff but I was doing this Goblin too
and I was trying to get all the
different angles so anyways he can kind
of spin in circles there I got all the
different angles I'm not sure if I love
love this one then I was messing with
the walk animation here but this was
really quick I haven't really tweaked
this or done anything this is kind of
how it just ended up without me tweaking
anything or working on the skeleton
stuff at all so you can see like kind of
what I I'd really have to go through and
touch up a lot of this it doesn't get
the colors right all the time you've got
to fix the colors and I I don't know I
don't know which way is better to do it
but certainly doing things like you know
if I were to just create a new file and
let's say I want a 32x 32 kind of
standard pixel art let's blow that up a
little bit bring it over here let's say
I wanted to create a I don't know an a
banana how about a banana we've got a
low top down so sort of a RPG style top
down you can pick high top down low top
down we're going to have it facing us
and we're going to do selective outline
you know what this time for fun let's do
black outline we'll do basic shading
this time just for fun and I don't know
let's see what happens if I do high
detail so anyways we're not even going
to say Target palette so it's just going
to ignore this palette it's just going
to make a a banana as best as it can and
you're going we're going to try to
generate a banana and I just I'm just
trying to show you how this program
works so you know sometimes I hit this
where you get in a q position so I'm
just going to I'm going to back out and
talk to you guys full screen here again
I'm yeah I'm really liking this OBS
Studio but oh okay
so that's the banana it's making this is
a pretty poor example of what I don't
know if I was trying to do a bunch of
bananas or what let's try retrying that
and see if it can do any better but
anyways that is what I've been working
on in a Sprite I don't know what I'm
going to do yet I really want to start
diving back into a couple tutorials
there's just a few game things I want to
get oh my my phone just dinged anyways
there's a few game things I want to get
back into and I want to I want to learn
how to do a few things that I haven't
done before like I especially want to
learn how to do a state machine there
are few other mechanics like inventory
systems and things like that I I want to
understand how to use
resources and yeah I've been looking at
a bunch of different things Lambda
functions and stuff so there's a few
different things I want to learn before
I go diving into another game of my own
but okay so here's kind of what it did
with bananas it's not great but it's not
terrible I mean you can see where it's
going we could back up and we could say
I don't know a bunch of bananas and see
if that helps at all to do anything but
that's where I'm at right now in my
journey oh boy it can't do bananas well
can it that's not doing well I thought
this would be a better example but this
is actually pretty surprising how poorly
it's doing let's go back and just do
something simple like you know actually
I'm curious is it the top down thing
maybe if I do the Sid scroller profile
maybe it'll do better let's see but oh
here it comes here it comes it's it's
getting there you know it's it's kind of
getting there but it's still not quite
great you get the idea I mean I don't
know I could just do a simple apple and
it'll do an apple anyways it it's a good
starting place for a person like me who
doesn't have a ton of time it's it's a
great way to get started and and there
you there you go though it's not quite
done yet but you can see where it's
heading with it yeah I mean that's
that's a nice looking Apple I didn't I
didn't have to make that so there are
certain cases where where this can work
out really well but I do believe there's
there's a lot of manual tweaking that
needs to be done so what I've done for
the past week or so is watched several
tutorials on how to use aprite so I just
have the general knowledge on how to use
the program so I can help tweak my work
a little bit but that's probably all I'm
going to show you I mean I'll end back
with this person walking I'm I'm really
proud of how that turned out yeah I
really I really like how that turned out
but that's that's what I've been doing
and I want to get back into game I got
to spark that thing back in me with
getting back into games and I think I
mentioned this in a different video but
one idea I had I do want to do these
tutorials and I was thinking maybe while
I do those tutorials I try and create my
own ass assets for those tutorials
usually when you follow a tutorial they
give you some basic asset pack to use
nothing too crazy and I thought I don't
know maybe I could make my own assets
and treat each tutorial like a mini game
that I'm trying to develop and who knows
maybe I'll even develop it into a mini
game and just go a little beyond the
tutorial or who knows maybe I'll take it
all the way into a full game you never
know I guess I want to explore a bit and
see where that takes me so that might be
one option I'm not necessarily giving up
on the idea of releasing an asset pack I
just got to figure out what I want to do
something like this sort of Tomb Raider
knockoff that I was working on it's a
lot of work it's a lot of work even with
the assistance of AI and I am not sure
that I want to put that amount of work
in to just release it for anybody to use
but then I would have to have a reason
to use it myself so it's it's difficult
anyways this video is much longer than I
originally intended it to be so I don't
know I don't know where I'm going to go
but I will keep you updated as I go
through this journey as I have been if
you guys have any questions on any of
this leave it in the comments comments
Below on Ace Sprite have you guys been
doing anything with your own pixel art
or anything like that I am an artist I
have been an artist I've I've done quite
a bit of Art in my lifetime it's just
not something I have a passion for as
much so it does it does make it
difficult to want to pursue that I I
much rather enjoy more the idea of
directing a video game I kind of view
myself as a as a indie game developer as
a director of sorts directing a video
game you know piecing it together doing
the code and all that stuff I enjoy that
so I want to focus a little more on that
but I probably need to learn a little
bit more of this pixel art stuff too so
that's where we're at for right now I
will just like I said I I'll let you
guys know as I continue to do stuff on
which direction I'm heading in if you
guys have any ideas or thoughts for me
too just leave them in the comments
below it does it does help to hear your
thoughts and ideas as well or even what
you're working on it it sometimes can
inspire me to do different things on
this channel or things on my own as I'm
working at becoming a full-time indie
game developer so we'll see what happens
but until next time keep youtubing it up
thanks for checking out neon dream games
Channel please make sure to like
subscribe and hit that Bell button so
you can stay up to dat on all the latest
videos we have to offer don't forget to
leave a comment to suggest what kind of
videos you'd like to see more of in the
future see you in the next video